Charlotte Bush

Brooklyn, NY | 202-441-7231 | clangbush@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/charlottebush7/ | https://github.com/Varlotte | https://dev.to/varlotte | https://femmefaust.us/dev

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Junior developer experienced in Python with Flask and JavaScript-based programming and a background in innovative learning experience design. Possesses strong skills in communication and managing projects and people to support company-wide goals. Award-winning off-off Broadway playwright and producer, and writer on triple-A video games.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Flask, SQL, JavaScript, React, Yaml, Flask-SQLalchemy, HTML and CSS, Wordpress, Confluence, Jira, Edmodo, Articulate360, Udemy, Blackboard, Final Cut Pro, Notion, Greenhouse, Zendesk, Salesforce, Tableau,

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

RXGnosis - Github- https://rxgnosis.com/

RXGnosis is a patient advocacy app to research and save a list of medications before doctor's appointments.

- Adapted peer reviewed federal data on medications and conditions (from Medline Plus) into yaml seed data on the backend for 4 common mental health diagnoses and 16 commonly-prescribed treatments.
- Created a full-stack app that works as "Tinder, for antidepressants" to make reliable data accessible for patients.
- Used Chakra component library to ensure coherent and ARIA-compliant styling throughout the app.

FlatStop - Github

FlatStop is a CLI application where users can access a game store interface to buy and sell video games.

- Refactored models and helper functions to maintain the single source of truth for the application.
- Contributed age-updating functionality to the user experience.
- Debugged browse store functions to make sure that the cart and sort pathways worked for the user.
- Acted as project manager to ensure scope and on-time delivery of goals.

DC Museum Archive - Github

The DC Museum Archive is a rating application for museums in the nation's capital.

- Created a custom database of DC-area museums customized to be filterable by react constraints.
- Collaborated on defining client-side routes for a landing page, museum lists, and specific museums.
- Created a form for users to add museums to the database that redirects on submit to the new museum.

EXPERIENCE

Care.com
Content and Process Specialist

Brooklyn, NY 2022-2022

Managed cross-departmental learning and development (L&D) initiatives meet learning goals across a 500 person organization. Part of the 15% of employees laid off during company-wide downsizing

- Led a cross-functional team to address new hire attrition, including data collection, project scoping, redesigning eLearning for onboarding and management best practices, and talent acquisition, affecting 200+ global employees
- Led a cross-functional team to address DEIB recruiting strategies. Created 12+ hours of new eLearning multimedia for this initiative
- Formed a new employee resource group for neurodiverse staff, affecting 50+ employees

Justworks
Onboarding Manager

Brooklyn, NY 2021-2022

Managed all aspects of a seamless onboarding onto the Justworks professional employer organization (PEO) platform for 50+ executives

- Successfully applied knowledge of instructional design to facilitate and enhance each business' month-long virtual onboarding experience while serving as the primary administrative point of contact
- Facilitated data-driven People Operations optimization support for small business and HR stakeholders

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Brooklyn, NY 07/2023 - 11/2023

Full Stack Web Development, Python with Flask and JavaScript program

CUNY Hunter College

New York, NY 06/2017

Master's of Science, Special Education